♪Holding hands silently as flowers fall and winds rise♪
♪يمسك الأيدي بصمت بينما تتساقط الزهور وترتفع الرياح♪
♪Dark tresses cascade like mountains. Dreams intertwine♪
♪خصلات داكنة تتدلى كالجبال. تتشابك الأحلام♪
♪Painting realms, clouds in palm, my brushwork for you♪
♪رسم العوالم، السحب في راحة اليد، فرشاتي لك♪
♪Light and shadow overlap my name across time and space♪
♪يتداخل الضوء والظل مع اسمي عبر الزمان والمكان♪
♪Across starry rivers, I chase dreams afar♪
♪عبر الأنهار المرصعة بالنجوم، أطارد الأحلام البعيدة♪
♪Arms spread wide, falling through heaven and earth♪
♪أذرع مفتوحة على مصراعيها، تسقط عبر السماء والأرض♪
♪The rhythm of breath and heartbeat♪
♪إيقاع التنفس ونبض القلب♪
♪A meeting of the souls♪
♪لقاء الأرواح♪
♪Through shifting seas and lands, I'd know you still♪
♪من خلال البحار والأراضي المتغيرة، سأظل أعرفك♪
♪Eyes bright as moonlit skies, untouched by worldly dust♪
♪عيون لامعة مثل سماء مضاءة بالقمر، غير متأثرة بغبار العالم♪
♪Smiling gazes write eternity♪
♪النظرات المبتسمة تكتب الخلود♪
=The Crush=
=السحق=
=Episode 12= (Protect Wife from Mother's Scheme)
=الحلقة ١٢= (حماية الزوجة من مكيدة الأم)
(Li Manor)
(قصر لي)
How did you convince Niaoniao to testify in court?
كيف أقنعت نياونياو بالشهادة في المحكمة؟
It wasn't exactly persuasion.
لم يكن إقناعًا تمامًا.
We were just using each other.
لقد كنا نستخدم بعضنا البعض فقط.
All their servitude contracts are held by Mr. Wang.
كل عقود العبودية الخاصة بهم يحتفظ بها السيد وانج.
Mr. Wang usually
السيد وانغ عادة
exploits and mistreats them.
يستغلهم ويعاملهم بشكل سيء.
Now that Mr. Wang is imprisoned,
الآن وقد تم سجن السيد وانغ،
they can naturally reclaim their contracts
يمكنهم استعادة عقودهم بشكل طبيعي
and regain their freedom.
واستعادة حريتهم.
A wonderful outcome.
نتيجة رائعة.
(Tianxiang Tea House)
(بيت الشاي تيانشيانغ)
Official business.
عمل رسمي.
(Sealed)
(مختوم)
(Top Milk Tea)
(شاي الحليب العلوي)
(24 Hours, Li's Milk Tea)
(24 ساعة، شاي الحليب لي)
(Li's Milk Tea)
(شاي الحليب لي)
(Game Mission)
(مهمة اللعبة)
(Sealed)
(مختوم)
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Hello. I'm Hassan.
مرحباً، أنا حسن.
(Hassan, Persian merchant) A Persian merchant.
(حسن تاجر فارسي) تاجر فارسي.
You must be Madam Li.
لا بد وأنك السيدة لي.
You know me?
أنت تعرفني؟
I've long heard of you.
لقد سمعت عنك منذ وقت طويل.
I've heard
لقد سمعت
- Young Master, look! - you're the inventor of milk tea.
- أيها السيد الشاب، انظر! - أنت مخترع شاي الحليب.
Look.
ينظر.
Not the inventor.
ليس المخترع.
More like an inspired adaptation.
أشبه بالتكيف الملهم.
- You're too modest. - Who's he?
- أنت متواضع جدًا. - من هو؟
He seems to be a merchant from Persia.
ويبدو أنه تاجر من بلاد فارس.
The taste
الطعم
is extraordinary.
أمر غير عادي.
But
لكن
I have a small suggestion.
عندي اقتراح صغير.
I wonder if I should tell you.
أتساءل هل يجب أن أخبرك؟
Go ahead.
تفضل.
Look.
ينظر.
Your milk tea costs several times more than regular tea,
شاي الحليب يكلف عدة مرات أكثر من الشاي العادي،
but ultimately, it's just a beverage.
لكن في نهاية المطاف، إنه مجرد مشروب.
It doesn't satisfy hunger.
فهو لا يشبع الجوع.
Only suitable for leisure.
مناسب للترفيه فقط.
If you add glutinous rice balls
إذا قمت بإضافة كرات الأرز الدبقة
and fruit pulp,
ولب الفاكهة،
it could serve not just as tea
يمكن أن يكون بمثابة الشاي وليس فقط
but also as sustenance.
ولكن أيضا كغذاء.
Why not just tell me
لماذا لا تخبرني فقط
to add pearls and coconut jelly?
إضافة اللؤلؤ وهلام جوز الهند؟
You also traveled to this world?
هل سافرت إلى هذا العالم أيضاً؟
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
I'm from Persia.
انا من بلاد فارس.
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
We'll all be friends from now on anyway.
سوف نكون جميعًا أصدقاء من الآن فصاعدًا على أي حال.
Nice working with you.
يسعدني العمل معك.
Young Master.
السيد الشاب.
What's this for?
ما هذا؟
Come, I'll show you inside.
تعال، سأريك الداخل.
Young Master, should we really hang this?
سيدي الشاب، هل يجب علينا حقًا تعليق هذا؟
Just hang it as told.
فقط قم بتعليقه كما قيل.
(Top Milk Tea) Young Master,
(شاي الحليب العلوي) السيد الشاب،
are you jealous?
هل انت غيور؟
Me?
أنا؟
(No Persians Allowed)
(لا يسمح للفرس)
Nobody removes this.
لا أحد يزيل هذا.
Understood?
مفهوم؟
(No Persians Allowed)
(لا يسمح للفرس)
Why exclude Persians?
لماذا نستبعد الفرس؟
Ignore that.
تجاهل ذلك.
Business as usual.
العمل كالمعتاد.
Do you guys hate Persians?
هل تكرهون الفرس؟
No.
لا.
Bigger than black beans, and smaller than grapes.
أكبر من الفاصوليا السوداء، وأصغر من العنب.
What are these soft and chewy things?
ما هي هذه الأشياء الناعمة والمضغوطة؟
These are called pearls.
هذه تسمى باللؤلؤ.
Try them.
جربهم.
Theoretically,
نظريا،
these should be made of cornstarch
ينبغي أن تكون مصنوعة من نشا الذرة
and sweet potato starch.
ونشا البطاطا الحلوة.
But
لكن
there is no such thing here,
لا يوجد شيء من هذا القبيل هنا،
so I had to use
لذلك كان علي أن أستخدم
other grains.
الحبوب الأخرى.
The taste must be similar.
يجب أن يكون الطعم مشابها.
Try it now.
جربه الآن.
Okay.
تمام.
It is tasty, right?
إنه لذيذ، أليس كذلك؟
Thanks to that Persian merchant.
بفضل هذا التاجر الفارسي.
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك،
I might have forgotten this entirely.
ربما نسيت هذا الأمر تماما.
Tasteless,
لا طعم له،
like chewing wax.
مثل مضغ الشمع.
Nothing special on their own.
لا يوجد شيء خاص في حد ذاته.
When being added in milk tea,
عند إضافته إلى شاي الحليب،
it becomes tasty.
يصبح لذيذًا.
I saw you chatting with that Persian today.
لقد رأيتك تتحدث مع ذلك الفارسي اليوم.
You seemed to be having a great conversation.
يبدو أنك تجري محادثة رائعة.
It was great.
لقد كان رائعا.
He shared numerous ideas
لقد شارك بالعديد من الأفكار
about milk tea improvement
حول تحسين شاي الحليب
and gave suggestions,
وأعطى اقتراحات،
which are quite reasonable.
والتي هي معقولة تماما.
Why discuss improvements with him?
لماذا مناقشة التحسينات معه؟
Why can't I
لماذا لا استطيع
discuss improvements with him?
مناقشة التحسينات معه؟
Why consult him?
لماذا استشارته؟
Why can't I
لماذا لا استطيع
consult him about improvements?
استشارته بشأن التحسينات؟
What I meant is,
ما قصدته هو،
why didn't you discuss it with me first?
لماذا لم تناقش هذا الأمر معي أولاً؟
I'm telling you right now, aren't I?
أنا أخبرك الآن، أليس كذلك؟
What's wrong with you today?
ماذا حدث لك اليوم؟
This was just a minor issue.
لقد كانت هذه مجرد مشكلة بسيطة.
Minor issue?
مشكلة بسيطة؟
This is between the two of us.
هذا بيننا الاثنين.
Why did you involve an outsider?
لماذا قمت بإشراك شخص من الخارج؟
Okay.
تمام.
I'll listen to you from now on.
سأستمع إليك من الآن فصاعدا.
In three days,
في ثلاثة أيام،
the Tea Merchants Guild is holding a banquet at Zhenxiu Restaurant.
جمعية تجار الشاي تقيم مأدبة في مطعم Zhenxiu.
You'll accompany me.
سوف ترافقني.
I won't go.
لن اذهب
The milk tea stall has
كشك شاي الحليب لديه
many things I need to attend to.
هناك الكثير من الأشياء التي يجب أن أهتم بها.
Go by yourself.
اذهب بنفسك.
You must come with me.
يجب عليك أن تأتي معي.
Why?
لماذا؟
This is the annual
هذا هو السنوي
tea convention in Haiqing Town.
مؤتمر الشاي في مدينة هايتشينغ.
All the veteran tea merchants will be there.
جميع تجار الشاي المخضرمين سيكونون هناك.
When you accompany me,
عندما ترافقني،
they'll know
سوف يعرفون
you are my wife,
انت زوجتي
the Madam of our family.
سيدة عائلتنا.
Public announcement?
إعلان عام؟
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
Fine, I'll go with you.
حسنًا، سأذهب معك.
Go with you.
اذهب معك.
Didn't you say it tasted bad?
ألم تقل أن طعمه سيئ؟
(Zhenxiu Restaurant) So you must be Madam Li.
(مطعم Zhenxiu) إذن يجب أن تكوني السيدة لي.
Let's toast to you!
دعونا نحتفل بك!
Xiaotang, here.
شياو تانغ، هنا.
To everyone.
الى الجميع.
Mr. Li,
السيد لي،
we'll need to rely on your family more often.
سوف نحتاج إلى الاعتماد على عائلتك في كثير من الأحيان.
Today, we must congratulate the Li family
اليوم يجب علينا أن نهنئ عائلة لي
on becoming Haiqing's top tea merchant.
على أن يصبح تاجر الشاي الأول في هايتشينج.
Your business
عملك
is thriving spectacularly.
تزدهر بشكل مذهل.
Here.
هنا.
You all flatter us.
أنتم جميعا تملقوننا.
All credit goes to my daughter-in-law.
كل الفضل يعود إلى زوجة ابني.
If not for her intelligence
إن لم يكن لذكائها
and dedication
والتفاني
in managing our family enterprises,
في إدارة مشاريعنا العائلية،
we wouldn't have today's success.
لم نكن لنحقق النجاح اليوم.
We should toast to her.
ينبغي علينا أن نحتفل بها.
I don't deserve such praise.
لا أستحق مثل هذا الثناء.
Madam Li.
Madam Li.
Another toast to everyone.
نخب آخر للجميع.
Madam Li, you are so excellent.
السيدة لي، أنت ممتازة جدًا.
I must
يجب علي
toast you again.
نخب لك مرة أخرى.
To Madam and Mr. Li
إلى السيدة والسيد لي
for eliminating that despicable Mr. Wang from our industry.
للقضاء على ذلك السيد وانج الحقير من صناعتنا.
My husband
زوجي
has been full of praise for Madam Li.
لقد كان مليئا بالثناء للسيدة لي.
Our duty.
واجبنا.
We've long heard of your wisdom and competence.
لقد سمعنا منذ فترة طويلة عن حكمتك وكفاءتك.
And today, I've found
واليوم وجدت
your reputation is deserved.
سمعتك تستحقها.
Let me toast to you again.
دعني أرفع لك نخبًا مرة أخرى.
We hope you will
نأمل أن تفعل ذلك
share more business strategies with us.
شارك المزيد من استراتيجيات الأعمال معنا.
Truly impressive.
مثير للإعجاب حقا.
Regarding business strategies,
فيما يتعلق باستراتيجيات الأعمال،
I do have some unique methods.
لدي بعض الأساليب الفريدة.
Miss.
يفتقد.
Excuse me for a moment.
عذرا للحظة واحدة.
You go ahead.
اذهب للأمام.
- Your daughter-in-law is a credit - What's wrong?
- زوجة ابنك هي الائتمان - ما هو الخطأ؟
- to your household management. - Hassan wants to discuss
- لإدارة منزلك. - حسن يريد مناقشة
trade cooperation with you in a room.
التعاون التجاري معك في الغرفة.
Business within our reach.
الأعمال في متناول أيدينا.
I'll check it out.
سأتحقق من ذلك.
Miss.
يفتقد.
Meeting a man privately will cause trouble.
إن لقاء رجل على انفراد سوف يسبب مشاكل.
It's fine.
إنه بخير.
Fetch Zixuan
جلب Zixuan
and have him come to the room.
وأطلب منه أن يأتي إلى الغرفة.
Cuicui.
كويكوي.
Lady, you summoned me?
سيدتي هل استدعيتني؟
I think I've had too much to drink.
أعتقد أنني شربت كثيرًا.
Bring me some tea.
احضر لي بعض الشاي.
Yes.
نعم.
Where is he?
أين هو؟
Hassan?
حسن؟
Madam Li.
Madam Li.
Everyone, together.
الجميع معًا.
Cheers.
هتافات.
Mr. Li.
السيد لي.
Miss Niaoniao.
السيدة نياونياو.
Have you seen my wife?
هل رأيت زوجتي؟
Madam Li
Madam Li
had too much to drink earlier.
لقد شربت كثيرًا في وقت سابق.
It seemed a man
لقد بدا وكأنه رجل
was helping her to a room.
كان يساعدها للوصول إلى الغرفة.
Hassan.
حسن.
Mr. Li,
السيد لي،
she likely drank too much.
من المرجح أنها شربت كثيرًا.
Please don't misunderstand.
من فضلك لا تسيء الفهم.
In a few days,
في غضون أيام قليلة،
I'll visit the temple to pray for my son's marital bliss.
سأزور المعبد للصلاة من أجل سعادة ابني الزوجية.
Good idea. Let's go together.
فكرة جيدة. لنذهب معًا.
Where's Madam Li?
أين السيدة لي؟
Madam Li?
Madam Li?
Zixuan! Zixuan!
زيكسوان! زيكسوان!
Zixuan, stop!
زيكسوان، توقف!
If any harm comes to my wife,
إذا حدث أي مكروه لزوجتي،
I'll kill you!
سأقتلك!
Exactly.
بالضبط.
I told you! Acting shamelessly without decency.
قلت لك! التصرف بلا خجل وبدون حياء.
Who'd have thought Mr. Wei's daughter
من كان يظن أن ابنة السيد وي
would be so frivolous?
هل سيكون الأمر تافهًا إلى هذه الدرجة؟
In broad daylight,
في وضح النهار،
she committed such shameless acts!
لقد ارتكبت مثل هذه الأفعال الوقحة!
Exactly.
بالضبط.
When I saw what was happening in that room,
عندما رأيت ما كان يحدث في تلك الغرفة،
even I was quite ashamed.
حتى أنني كنت أشعر بالخجل الشديد.
She caused such a scandal
لقد تسببت في مثل هذه الفضيحة
and made it known to all!
وأعلم الجميع بذلك!
How will the women of our family
كيف ستتصرف نساء عائلتنا؟
face people hereafter?
مواجهة الناس في الآخرة؟
Sister,
أخت،
we all know you value propriety most.
نحن نعلم جميعًا أنك تقدر الملاءمة أكثر من أي شيء آخر.
A hussy like Wei Xiaotang
أجش مثل وي شياو تانغ
deserves to be divorced!
يستحق الطلاق!
Yes! Divorce is the only way.
نعم! الطلاق هو الحل الوحيد.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
This scandal caused huge uproars.
وقد أثارت هذه الفضيحة ضجة كبيرة.
If she's not divorced,
إذا لم تكن مطلقة،
how can you and your family hold your heads high?
كيف يمكنك أنت وعائلتك أن ترفعوا رؤوسكم عالياً؟
True.
حقيقي.
(Wei Xiaotang,)
(وي شياو تانغ،)
(once a woman gets tainted,)
(عندما تتلوث المرأة)
(even if her husband dotes on her,)
(حتى لو كان زوجها يحبها)
(he can't protect her.)
(لا يستطيع حمايتها.)